Abdul Quadri Jimoh

Lagos, Nigeria | <u>olamide14044@gmail.com</u> | +2349091385211 https://github.com/Abu-Abdillah1/git-us | linkedin.com/in/abdul-quadri-jimoh-69369714a

Summary:

A Full Stack (MERN) engineer with 2+ years of experience and a strong background in software development. Experienced in turning product design requirements into user interfaces, using JavaScript, Node.js, React, and related technologies. Proficient in TypeScript, database technologies, server-side technologies, unit testing, integration testing frameworks, Git, debugging, and troubleshooting. Strong understanding of web application architecture and design patterns. Experience with cloud platforms, Docker, and Agile development methodologies. Possess a bachelor's degree in computer science & IT.

Skills:

- JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, C, Python, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind CSS.
- React JS, Next JS, Node JS, Express JS, Nest JS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite, REST API, GraphQL.
- Git, Docker, CI/CD Pipeline, Jest, Shell

Work Experience:

Node JS Backend Engineer, Soundmac Global LTD - Contract

February 2023 - Present

- Design and implement RESTful APIs to enable efficient distribution of music by the users using Node.js, TypeScript, MongoDB.
- Implement user authentication and authorization using JWT
- Design, implement and optimize databases, queries, and data models
- Write clean, maintainable, and efficient code
- Write automated tests using Jest to ensure code quality and maintainability
- Participate in code reviews and provide feedback to other team members

Full Stack Engineer, Ilerioluwa Block Industry

August 2021 – Present

- Develop fully functional responsive ecommerce application for selling building materials with scalable and efficient web applications using MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js)
- Design and implement RESTful APIs to interface with front-end applications
- Implement user authentication and authorization using JWT
- Automated pipeline using GitHub workflow to automated CI/CD process
- Engage with other parts of the Engineering/Development team as well as the Product function to facilitate the development & delivery of platform functionality requirements
- Write clean, maintainable, and efficient code
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to improve development efficiency
- Contribute to the conversation to bring ideas on improvement, technology development, and iteration

- Troubleshoot and debug issues across the full stack
- Write automated tests to ensure code quality and maintainability
- Participate in code reviews and provide feedback to other team members
- Keep up-to-date with the latest web development trends and technologies
- Contribute to the development of technical documentation
- Collaborate with product managers to turn product design requirements into user interfaces
- Utilize TypeScript, server-side technologies (Node js), unit testing and integration testing frameworks (Jest), and Git for version control

Access Solutions LTD (Software Engineer Intern)

March 2021 - August 2021

- Collaborated with senior software engineers to design, develop, and test software applications
- Contributed to the development of a new feature for the company's flagship product using Java and MySQL
- Participated in code reviews and provided feedback to improve code quality
- Documented software design and implementation details
- Assisted in troubleshooting and resolving software defects

Projects:

Super exchange | code | doc

 A current exchange ecommerce with full functionalities developed with Node, Express, TypeScript, MongoDB, Jest.

Prime | code | doc

• Fully functional blogging API developed with Node, Express, TypeScript, Prisma, Jest.

GitUs | code | live

• Mobile web app that consumes GitHub API developed with React JS, TypeScript, and Chakra UI.

Education:

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & IT (4.78/5.0) – First Class Honors

Federal University Dutsin-Ma, December 2022

References:

Available upon request.